heals.co.uk 2015-06-26

# Privacy Policy | Heal's

What are cookies?

Cookies are very small pieces of information that are created then stored on your computer, smart phone or tablet when you visit certain web pages. At Heal's, we use cookies to speed up and personalise your browsing experience. For example, we use cookies if you have visited our website before, keep track of what you have in your basket and tailor product recommendations to help with your purchasing decisions.

As part of Heal's commitment to comply with recent legislation changes, and to ensure that we are absolutely clear about your privacy when using our website, we have detailed full information on cookies and how we use them on heals.co.uk

Cookies & how they affect you

Completely harmless to your computer, cookies don't store personally identifiable information such as name, address or payment details, but they do provide us with encrypted information to help improve your experience of the site. For example, they help us to identify errors, suggest related and recommended products and allow you to connect with social media sites such as Facebook, Twitter, Google+ and Pinterest.

 _There are four types of cookies:_

\- Strictly necessary cookies  
\- Performance cookies  
\- Functionality cookies  
\- Targeting or advertising cookies.

A list of all the cookies used on the Website by category is set out below.

Strictly Necessary Cookies

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the Website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the Website. Without these cookies, basic functions such as add to bag, stay logged in and checkout are not possible.

**Cookie Name** | **First or Third Party Name** | **Purpose of Cookie**  
---|---|---  
locn | heals.co.uk | Being able to select which currency you want to shop in.  
lang | heals.co.uk | Being able to select which language to view the website in.  
RFID | heals.co.uk | Used for you to add products to your basket and log into your account.  
SID | heals.co.uk | Collects session ID for the purposes of session control.  
RVI | heals.co.uk | Collects list of recently viewed items for the purposes of displaying 'recently viewed items'.  
vbmprods | heals.co.uk | Collects list of recently viewed items for the purposes of displaying 'recommended items' to you.  
vbmtracker | heals.co.uk | Collects recommended items tracking code for the purposes of building 'recommended items' data.  
referid | heals.co.uk | Referral data to track sites that link to ours so we can track this information.  
httprefer | heals.co.uk | Referral data to track sites that link to ours so we can track this information.  
Setview | heals.co.uk | Keeps your preference for the product information display page.  
setViewPerPage | heals.co.uk | Keeps your preference for the number of products to view per page.  
RSI | heals.co.uk | Keeps last 3 keyword searches for the purpose of displaying the last 3 key words so users can quickly go back to them.  
Quench | heals.co.uk | Managing performance on our site to ensure it's as quick as possible for you.  

Performance Cookies

These cookies collect information about how you use the Website, for instance which pages you go to most often, and if you get error messages from web pages. These cookies don't collect information that identifies you personally. Any information gained is to improve the way the Website works.

**Cookie Name** | **Third Party Name** | **Purpose of Cookie**  
---|---|---  
__utma, __utmb, __utmz, uid, __utma, __utmb, __utmz | Google Analytics | Enables us to track and improve our website based on analysing results and behaviours of our customers.  
pfa.levexis.com LGP, TMP, TMS, TMTV, TMDT, TMDTS_SEC  | Tagman | Enables us to control the tags which are served on to our web pages and the data passed into those tags or into TagMan reporting. The TagMan system allows Heal's to tracks users who have viewed our online marketing campaigns or visited our websites. 

TagMan cookies help us to measure and analyse how our website and marketing campaigns have performed, so that we can improve our site, our marketing campaigns and therefore provide our customers with a better, more personalised shopping experience.  

Functionality Cookies

These cookies remember choices you make to improve your experience and allow the Website to provide enhanced and more personal features.

**Cookie Name** | **Third Party Name** | **Purpose of Cookie**  
---|---|---  
Lu, x-src, datr | Facebook | Enable Facebook like and social interaction at Heal's.  
pid, guest_id, k  | Twitter | Enable Twitter share and social interaction at Heal's.  
_pinterest_sess, csrftoken, 229774877, __utmv  | Pinterest | Enable Pinterest Pinit button and social interaction at Heal's.  

Targeting or Advertising Cookies

These cookies collect information about your browsing habits in order to make advertising relevant to you and your interests.

These cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. They are usually placed by advertising networks with our permission. Quite often targeting or advertising cookies will be linked to site functionality.

Further info about cookies

If you would like to learn more about cookies in general, how they work and how to manage them, we recommend that you visit [aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

Managing Cookies

If you want to purchase from our website you must ensure cookies are enabled on your browser – here's how to do it:

| Internet Explorer: | 1\. Click on 'Tools' in your browser window, then on 'Internet Options'.  
2\. Under the 'Privacy' tab, ensure your setting is at medium in order for cookies to work.  
3\. Click Apply then OK.   
---|---|---  
| Firefox: | 1\. Click on 'Tools' in your browser window and then on 'Options'.  
2\. Select the 'Privacy' icon, click on 'Cookies', then select 'accept cookies from sites'.  
3\. Click OK.   
| Google Chrome: | 1\. Click on 'Settings' in your browser window and then on 'Advanced settings'.  
2\. Under 'Privacy', click 'Content settings' ensure 'allow local data to be set' is selected.  
3\. Click OK.   
| Safari (PC) | 1\. Click on the 'Cog' icon in your browser window and then on 'Preferences'.  
2\. Click the 'Privacy' tab and under 'Block cookies' and chose 'Never'.  
3\. Close the box.   
| Safari (Mac) | 1\. Click on 'Safari' in your browser window and select 'Preferences'.  
2\. Click 'Security' and choose to accept cookies 'always' or 'only from sites I visit'.  
3\. Close the box.   
  
Privacy Policy

The purpose of this statement is to set out how we use personal information we may obtain about you. By registering as a user of the services provided by Heal's and by using the Heal's web site generally you agree to this use. 

1\. When you register and use this site you will be asked to provide certain information such as your contact details. We will store this data and hold it on computers or otherwise. We will use this data to fulfil our agreement with you.

2\. We may use the information you provide:

\- To register you with our website and to administer our website services. 

\- For assessment and analysis (e.g. market, customer and product analysis) to enable us to review, develop and improve the services we offer and to enable us to provide you and other customers with relevant information through our marketing programme. We may use your information to make decisions about you using computerised technology, for example, automatically selecting products or services, that we think will interest you from the information we have. We may inform you (by email, mail or otherwise) about products and services that we consider may be of interest to you. If you do not wish Heal's to use your information for marketing purposes, please tick the opt-out box provided when registering. 

\- We do occasionally make names and addresses (but never email addresses) available to companies whose products we think may interest you, unless you have told us not to. If you do not wish to receive such offers please email [privacy@heals.co.uk](mailto:privacy@heals.co.uk) with 'unsubscribe to 3rd party' in the subject field. 

\- For the prevention and detection of fraud. 

\- To administer any prize draws or competitions you may enter. 

3\. If at a later date you wish to opt out of receiving marketing information from Heal's, you can unsubscribe by sending an email to [enquiries@heals.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@heals.co.uk) with 'unsubscribe' in the subject field.

4\. We may give information about you to the following, who may use it for the same purposes as set out above:

\- To employees and agents of Heal's to administer any accounts, products and services provided to you by Heal's now or in the future.

\- Agents who profile your data so that we can tailor the goods/services we offer to your specific needs.

We may also disclose your information:

\- To anyone to whom we transfer or may transfer our rights and duties under our agreement with you.

\- If we have a duty to do so or if the law allows us to do so.

5\. In order that we can monitor and improve the site, we may gather certain information about you when you use it, including details of your domain name and IP address, operating system, browser version and the website you visited prior to our site.

6\. New technologies are emerging on the Internet that help us to deliver customised visitor experiences. In particular, there is a technology called 'cookies', which may be used by us to provide you with customised information from our website. A cookie is an element of data that a website can send to your browser, which may then store it on your system. Cookies allow us to understand who has seen which pages and advertisements, to determine how frequently particular pages are visited and to determine the most popular areas of our website. Cookies also allow us to make our website more user friendly by, for example, allowing us to save your password so that you do not have to re-enter it every time you visit our website. We use cookies so that we can give you a better experience when you return to our website. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. You do not have to accept cookies, and you should read the information that came with your browser software to see how you can set up your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. This will give you the opportunity to decide whether to accept it.

7\. We may supplement the information you provide us with information we receive from third parties.

8\. We endeavour to take all reasonable steps to protect your personal details. However, we cannot guarantee the security of any data you disclose online. You accept the inherent security risks of providing information and dealing online over the Internet and will not hold us responsible for any breach of security unless this is due to our negligence or willful default.

9\. You have the right to see personal data (as defined in the Data Protection Act) we keep about you - upon receipt of a written request and payment of a fee of £10. If you are concerned that any of the information we hold on you is incorrect please contact us.

10\. Please note that any products and services are supplied subject to our standard terms and conditions. If you have any comments or queries in connection with our privacy policy, please email us at [enquiries@heals.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@heals.co.uk)
